Janessa Perry

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

hello@janessaperry.com (604) 445-7177 linkedin.com/in/janessa-perry github.com/janessaperry

PROFILE

My interest in digital solutions began as a Research Analyst, where I designed KPI dashboards in collaboration with developers to ensure functionality and technical feasibility. This led me to design and develop the company website, and later take charge of the survey platform, working with technologies like Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Twig. After five years, I transitioned to freelancing where I designed an online learning platform for Indigenous adults to access educational credits remotely. With a background in design and a recent Diploma in Software Engineering, I'm eager to continue solving problems and building functional digital solutions.

SKILLS

Front-End Development, Back-End Development, Agile Development, APIs, User Authentication, CMS, Version Control [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM APIs, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass, Twig, REST APIs, Postman, React JS, Node.js, Express, MySQL, VSCode, Git, GitHub, Chrome DevTools, Netlify, WordPress]

UX/UI Design, Prototyping, Wireframing, Visual Design, Responsive Design, Accessible Design [Figma, Affinity Suite, Design Systems]

Asana, Slack, Microsoft 365 [PowerPoint, Excel, Word]

PROJECTS

UI Designer & Full-Stack Developer | Press Start

DEC 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

• Leveraged design and full-stack development skills to create a website that helps users keep track of their video game collection and decide what to play next.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

SEP 2024 - DEC 2024, VANCOUVER, BC

BrainStation | Certificates in UX Design & UI Design

FEB 2018 - JUN 2018, VANCOUVER, BC

Ryerson University | Bachelor of Commerce

SEP 2009 - APR 2013, TORONTO, ON [DEAN'S LIST]
Nominated for Gordon Taylor Future Researchers Undergraduate Award

EXPERIENCE

Web Designer | Freelance

JUL 2022 - PRESENT, RICHMOND, BC

- Deliver user-friendly WordPress websites and provide documentation to enable clients to manage and update their sites independently after launch [WordPress, Figma, HTML, CSS, JS].
- Design and develop internal tools and resources to streamline workflow and improve productivity [Word, Excel].
- Designed an online learning platform for Indigenous adults, improving access to high school credits in remote areas [Figma].

Manager, UI Design & Project Solutions | The Sentis Group

SEP 2017 - APR 2022, VANCOUVER, BC [PROMOTED TO MANAGER IN SEP 2021]

- Led the design and development of the survey platform, ensuring all features met user needs and optimized for cross-browser and device compatibility [Figma, HTML, CSS, JS, Twig].
- Trained new hires in survey programming fundamentals and maintained comprehensive platform documentation to support onboarding.
- Leveraged a variety of tools and technologies to design and maintain Sentis' website and brand collateral [Figma, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Affinity Suite].
- Collaborated with project managers and full-stack developers to design KPI dashboards, empowering clients to make data-driven decisions [Figma].

Project Manager | The Sentis Group

SEP 2013 - SEP 2017, VANCOUVER, BC [PROMOTED TO MANAGER IN SEP 2015]

- Managed multiple projects across lifecycle stages, coordinating cross-functional teams to ensure timely and high quality deliverables.
- Designed custom online reporting sites based on client needs, collaborating closely with developers to ensure usability and functionality.
- Cleaned and prepared sample data to ensure accurate survey distribution supporting effective data collection.